Guide to the Ernst Weber Collection RG.033
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series V: Publications
  - Subseries C: Magazine and Newspaper Clippings
    - Newspaper clippings, German, 1972-1988 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Subseries D: Technical Reports and Periodicals
    - Technical reports, 1948-1967 (Box 22)
    - Bulletins, 1964-1985 (Box 22)
    - American Heritage, 1985-1990 (Box 22)
    - Bell Telephone Laboratories, 1928 - 1940; 1948-1950 (Box 23)
    - Mechanical Engineering, 1933 (Box 24)
    - Physics Today, 1991 (Box 24)
    - Science, 1980-1992 (Box 24)
    - Western Electric Company, 1923-1924 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous journals, 1929-1991 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous magazines, 1961-1984 (Box 24)
  - Subseries E: Books and Book Excerpts
    - Book excerpts and chapters, undated (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Chapters on feedback, undated (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Monographs, 1960-1965 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Monographs, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - German language monographs, 1928-1976 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - HI Carrier Telephone System, 1937 (Box 25, Item 1)
    - Foundations of Sand: A hard look at the soft sciences, 1982 (Box 25, Item 2)
    - New York State and Private Higher Education, 1968 (Box 25, Item 3)
    - Continuing Engineering Studies: A report of the joint advisory committee, 1964 (Box 25, Item 4)
    - Experiment and Theory in Physics, 1943 (Box 25, Item 5)
    - Waves: A mathematical account of the common types of wave motion, 1947 (Box 25, Item 6)
    - Turning Points in Physics: A series of lectures given at Oxford University in Trinity Term 1958, 1959 (Box 25, Item 7)
    - Briefe zur Wellenmechanik, 1963 (Box 25, Item 8)
    - An Introduction to Servo-Mechanisms, 1953 (Box 25, Item 9)
    - Science and Technology Advice to the President, Congress, and Judiciary, 1993 (Box 25, Item 10)
- Series VI: Professional Organizations
  Many of these professional organizations merged or overlapped. The American Institute of Electrical Engineers (AIEE) was founded 1884. The Institute of Radio Engineers (IRE) was founded in 1912 and merged with AIEE in 1963 to form the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE). Weber was the first president of IEEE.
  The National Academy of Sciences (NAS), National Research Council (NRC), and National Academy of Engineering (NAE) are all part of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine. NAS was founded in 1863, NRC was founded in 1916, and NAE was founded in 1964. Weber was involved in all of these organizations and he often combined more than one entity in his folders and notes.
  - Subseries A: AIEE
    - AIEE notes, 1935-1941 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - AIEE "Institute Activities", 1942 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - AIEE Symposium on Ferromagnetic Circuits, 1949 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Nomination of Dr. Ernst Weber for AIEE Medal in Electrical Engineering Education, 1956 May (Box 25, Item 11)
    - AIEE reprints, 1938-1950 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - AIEE reprints, 1952-1962 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Subseries B: IRE
    - "Ernst Weber- Pres. IRE", 1955-1959 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - IRE correspondence, 1959-1962 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - "IRE Travels Plan", 1959 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - IRE "Proposed Definitions of Terms in the Field of Linear Varying Parameter and Nonlinear Circuits", 1953 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - IRE reprints, 1938-1949 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - IRE reprints, 1950-1962 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Proceedings of the IRE: 50th Anniversary Issue, 1962 May (Box 26, Item 1)
  - Subseries C: IEEE
    - IEEE clippings, 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - IEEE Spectrum clippings, 1966-1973 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - IEEE Spectrum clippings, 1974-1990 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE clippings, 1971-1973 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE clippings, 1974-1976 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE clippings, 1977-1979 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE clippings, 1980-1988 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - IEEE Transactions on Microwave Theory and Technique Clippings, 1971, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - IEEE Transactions on Engineering Management, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - IEEE Transactions on Education clippings, 1976-1977 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - IEEE Circuits and Systems magazine clippings, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Engineering Manpower Projections, undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Letter Symbols for Quantities used in Electrical science and Electrical Engineering, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - IEEE Transactions on Magnetics, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - IEEE conference papers, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - IEEE transactions papers, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - IEEE Spectrum reprint, 1965 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control reprints, 1967, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - IEEE Transactions on Antennas and propagation reprints, 1966-1972 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - IEEE Transactions on Microwave Theory and Technique reprint, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE reprints, 1963, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - The IEEE Antennas and Propagation Society 1942-1982, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Proposed IEEE paper, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - The Joint Telecommunications Advisory Committee, 1948-1979 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - IEEE newsletters, 1976, 1982-1989 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - IEEE programs, 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - IEEE Centennial, Boston, MA, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Electrical Engineering...Today's View of the Profession, undated (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Selected Papers in Digital Signal Processing II, 1975 (Box 27)
    - IEEE Spectrum, 1991-1992 (Box 27)
    - IEEE Transaction Circuits and Systems, 1981-1982 (Box 27)
    - IEEE Transaction Circuit Theory, 1964, 1971 (Box 27)
    - Annual Proceedings, 1974-1977 (Box 27)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE, 1971-1977 (Box 27)
    - Proceedings of the IEEE, 1978-1991 (Box 28)
  - Subseries D: NAS
    - NAS letters to members, 1973-1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - NAS correspondence, Philip Handler, 1972-1974 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - NAS "Report to Dr. Handler", 1972 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - NAS Philip Handler (1917-1981) Tribute, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - NAS program budgets, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - NAS proposals for nomination, undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - NAS "Advisory Appointments", 1970-1976 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - NAS council actions, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - NAS 110th annual meeting, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - NAS "A Plan for the Organization, Governance, and Operation of the National Research Council", 1971 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - NAS "Science in the Context of Society" draft and notes, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - NAS "News Report", 1972-1976 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - NAS "Report by the Committee on Motor Vehicle Emissions", 1973 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - NAS "Report of the Foreign Secretary", 1974 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - NAS "Report of the Home Secretary", 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - NAS "Annual report of the President", 1976 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - NAS publications and clippings, 1934-1939; 1969-1973 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - NAS programs, 1963, 1980, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - National Academy of Sciences Biographical Memoirs volumes 42-45, 47-48, 50-56, 60, 1972-1991 (Volume 42-45, 47-48, 50-56, 60)
    - Annual Report of the National Academy of Sciences (7 monographs), 1968-1977 (Volume 1968/1969, 1970/1971, 1971/1972, 1973/1974, 1974/1975, 1975/1976, 1976/1977)
    - Organization and Members NAS/NAE/IOM/NRC (12 monographs), 1969-1973, 1975-1982 (Volume 1969-1973; 1975-1982)
  - Subseries E: NRC
    - NRC correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - NRC correspondence and notes, 1971-1972 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - Relationships between NRC-NEA-NAS, correspondence and minutes, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - NRC "Institute for Systems Analysis, Laxenburg, Wien", 1974 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - NRC bulletin and news, 1919, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - NRC Silver Anniversary Dinner, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - NRC brochure, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - NRC Commission on Sociotechnical Systems (CSS), 1976 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - NRC Commission on Sociotechnical Systems (CSS) staff list and agenda, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - NRC Commission on Sociotechnical Systems (CSS) proposal, correspondence, and notes, 1973-1975 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - NRC critical issues and long range planning for CSS, 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - Automated Decision Making and its Vulnerabilities, CSS, research, and notes, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - NRC Vulnerabilities in Automated Design-Making, 1st Draft "Think Piece," correspondence and notes, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - Automated Decision Making and its Vulnerabilities, CSS, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - NRC Task Force on Automated Information and Design-Making, CSS, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - NRC Proposed Program Outline, Commission Task Force on Automated Design-Making, 1977-1978 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - NRC Bulletin, 1922 (Item 4)
  - Subseries F: NAE
    - NAE reports sent to Committee of the 25, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - NAE Committee of the 25, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - NAE Committee on the 25 correspondence and notes, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - NAE Joint Technical Advisory Council, 1962-1973 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - NAE minutes and memos, 1965-1973 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - NAE News to Members, 1973-1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - NAE clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - NAE reports and proposals, 1961-1969 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - NAE publications, 1976-1990 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Plans for the future relations of NAS-NAE-NRC, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - "Replies to Weber's NAS-NAE letters", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Weber's NAS-NAE_NRC notes, 1969-1973 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Weber's NAS and Poly notes, "Current Matters, Pending", 1967-1969 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - NAE Memorial Tributes, 1979 (Item 1)
    - NAE Directory of Member and Foreign Associations, 1988 (Item 2)
    - NAE Members, 1975 (Item 3)
  - Subseries G: Miscellaneous Professional Correspondence
    - Weber Congressional Action, 1960-1970 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Engineers Council for Professional Development, 1971-1972 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Bern Dibner, 1964-1987 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Lawrence Hafsted, 1982-1983 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence with professional organizations, 1964-1978 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence regarding publications, 1959-1969 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence regarding publications, 1970-1987 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Subseries H: Miscellaneous Symposia
    - AAAS Symposium, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Symposium of the Federal Government of Austria, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Symposium: Future of Science and Technology in Austria, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Symposium: Future of Science and Technology in Austria, 1972 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - World Congress on Educating Engineering for World Development, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Subseries I: Miscellaneous Brochures, Reports, Photographs and Correspondence
    - National Medal of Science program, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Institution and Conference brochures, 1955-1978 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Westinghouse, 1965-1970 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Harris Corporation, 1975-1981 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Defense Science Board, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Defense Science Board, Technical Civilian Personnel, 1964-1965 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Municipal Service Commission, 1925-1930 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Municipal Civil Service exams, 1925-1926 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Municipal Civil Service exams, 1927-1928 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Municipal Civil Service exams, 1929-1930 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Municipal Civil Service exams, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - RCA Manufacturing Company, 1935-1939 (Box 31, Item 1)
    - RCA Radiotron Company, 1934-1935 (Box 31, Item 2)
    - U-CARE, 1964-1969 (Box 31, Item 3)
    - Arab Institute for Aerospace Technology in Cairo preliminary study, 1978 June (Box 31, Item 4)
    - Minutes of the Association of Independent Engineering Colleges, 1970 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Professional contact list in German, undated (Box 31, Folder 13)
- Series VII: Oversize
  - Scientific American, 1845 August 28 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Lecture notes and graphs, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Awards and citations, 1958-1984 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Republican Senatorial Inner Circle photographs, circa 1990s (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Polytechnic Alumni Association Annual Dinner, 1965 (Box 32, Item 1)
  - Polytechnic Alumni Association Annual Dinner, 1963 (Box 32, Item 2)
  - Polytechnic Alumni Association Annual Dinner, 1962 (Box 32, Item 3)
  - Polytechnic Alumni Association Annual Dinner, 1958 (Box 32, Item 4)
  - Brooklyn Polytechnic Alumni Loan Fund Dance, 1958 (Box 32, Item 5)